one way of cheating on associativity is
called way prediction we start with a
set associative cache which has a low
miss rate but would have a slow hit time
now what we do we guess which line in
the set is the most likely to hit so
what we do is we use the index bits to
determine which side should we'll be
looking at and now instead of reading
out all the tags in that line and
checking which one hits we guess which
one is the likely to hit and just check
that one so this gives us the access
time similar to a direct mapped cache if
we guessed right if we are wrong then we
got no hit on the line we tried but the
set has other lines so we try a normal
set associative check which will have a
higher hit time so the idea is that
overall our miss rate is that of a set
associative cache we either find it this
way or this way so the Miss rate will be
similar to a set associative cache
because even if we didn't find it in a
kind of direct mapped way we will find
it this way but the hit time if what
gases are mostly right is mostly that of
a direct mapped cache so we have
combined the low miss rate of a set
associative cache with most of the time
getting the hit time of a direct mapped
cache and sometimes only having to
suffer the longer hit time of a normal
set associative cache